前情提要
权力的游戏
I want you to tell me the truth about Joffrey.
我希望你告訴我喬佛裏的真相
He's a monster.
他是個魔鬼
With the Tyrells beside us,
有了提利爾家族與我們聯合
no one will think of rebelling for another century.
再過一百年也沒人敢叛亂
Ser Dontos from House of Hollard
霍拉德家族的唐托斯爵士
Ser Meryn, help Ser Dontos to celebrate my Nameday
梅泰林爵士，灌死唐托斯爵士來慶祝我的命名日
It would be bad luck to kill a man on your nameday.
在您的命名日殺人很不吉利
You'll be my new fool.
你就當我的新弄臣吧
Thank you, Your Grace.
謝謝您，陛下
Do you know what it takes
你知道怎樣才能
to unite
團結19個部落嗎？
I told them we were all going to die.
我告訴他們如果不去南方
If we don't get out.
我們都會死
Let us go, my father will pay you whatever you want.
讓我們走，無論你要什麼，我父親都會給
Enough to buy me a new head?
夠我買個新腦袋嗎？
無垢者！
殺了奴隸主
殺了士兵
We need to find Sansa Stark a husband.
我們需要給珊莎·史塔克找個丈夫
Tyrion will do as he's bid and will marry Ser Loras.
提利昂會履行他的職責，而你要嫁給洛拉斯爵士
- I am not some brood mare. - You're my daughter!
- 我不是什麼種母馬
- 你是我女兒！
My feelings for you have not changed.
我對你的感情沒變
I'm not your lady, I'm you whore.
我不是你的夫人，我是你的妓女
He's a Crow. He'll stab us in the back.
他是個烏鴉，他會在背後捅死我們
Kill him.
殺了他
That's a fine little blade.
這把小劍真不錯
Something wrong with your leg, boy?
你腿有問題嗎，孩子？
You got to carry me.
你得背著我
Robb.
羅柏
The Lannisters send their regards.
蘭尼斯特家族表示問候
Too late.
來不及了
You know I didn't have a choice.
你知道我別無選擇
You know nothing, Jon Snow.
你什麼都不知道，瓊恩·雪諾
Your home.
你到家了
-=TLF字幕组=-
荣誉出品
♪ Game of Thrones 4x01 ♪ Two Swords Original Air Date on April 6, 2014
翻译：Lydia萌
翻译：Hello Agnes
翻译：versus
君临
King's Landing
翻译：潜潜小保
翻译：LordVader
校对：LordVader
特效：飞翔的鸡
统筹：饭离烨
龙石岛
DragonStone
恐怖堡
Dreadfort
临冬城
WinterFell
根据乔治·R·R·马丁著《冰与火之歌》改编
权利的游戏
第四季   第一集
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
电视剧编剧
戴维·贝尼奥夫 & D·B·威斯
导演
D·B·威斯
两柄剑
- Magnificent. - Mm-hmm.
精美絕倫
Looks fresh-forged.
像新鑄的
It is.
確實
No one's made a Valyrian steel sword
自從瓦雷利亞浩劫之後
since the Doom of Valyria.
就沒人能鑄瓦雷利亞鋼劍了
There are three living smiths
世上還有三名鐵匠
who know how to rework Valyrian steel.
知道如何重鑄瓦雷利亞鋼
The finest of them was in Volantis.
其中手藝最好的就在瓦蘭提斯
Came here to King's Landing at my invitation.
受我邀請來到了君臨
Where did you get this much Valyrian steel?
你從哪弄到這麼多瓦雷利亞鋼的？
From someone who no longer had need of it.
從某個不再需要的人手裏
You've wanted one of these in the family for a long time.
你一直都想在家族裏添一柄這劍
- And now we have two. - Two?
- 而現在有了兩柄
- 兩柄？
The original weapon was absurdly large.
原來那把大得荒唐
Plenty of steel for two swords.
足夠鑄造兩柄劍
Well, thank you. It's glorious.
謝謝您，非常精美
You'll have to train your left hand.
你必須練習用左手
Any decent swordsman knows how to use both hands.
所有像樣的劍士雙手都會用劍
You'll never be as good.
你不會再像以前一樣厲害了
No.
不會了
But as long as I'm better than everyone else,
但只要我還比其他人出色
I suppose it doesn't matter.
我覺得就無所謂
You can't serve in the Kingsguard with one hand.
一隻手沒法效力御林鐵衛
Where's that written? I can and I will.
哪寫著的？我能，也會繼續效力
The Kingsguard oath is for life.
御林鐵衛的宣誓終生有效
The war is over. The king is safe.
戰爭結束了，國王安全了
The king is never safe.
國王永遠不會安全
How many people in this city alone would love to see his head on a pike?
只這一座城裏就有多少人想看他腦袋插在槍尖上？
Other knights protected the king while you were a prisoner.
你被俘的時候有其他騎士保護國王
They will continue to do so when you go home.
在你回家後他們也會繼續效力
- Home? - You'll return to Casterly Rock
- 回家？
- 你要回凱巖城
<i>and rule in my stead.</i>
<i>代替我統治</i>
You are the Lord of Casterly Rock.
你才是凱巖城的公爵
I am the King's Hand. My place is here.
我是國王之手，我的職責在此
I don't expect to see the Rock again before I die.
我不指望死前還能看到凱巖城了
You know what they call me?
你知道他們叫我什麼嗎？
Kingslayer. Oathbreaker.
弒君者，背誓者
Man without honor.
沒有榮譽的人
Now you want me to break another sacred vow.
你想讓我再背棄一條神聖誓言
You won't be breaking anything.
你什麼也不用背棄
There is a precedent to relieve a Kingsguard of his duties.
御林鐵衛被免除職責是有過先例的
The king will exercise that prerogative.
國王會再次行使這項特權
- No. - No?
- 不
- 不？
No.
不
I don't believe I asked you a question.
我沒有問你問題
There's my answer.
這就是我的答案
If you think your bloody honor comes before--
如果你認為你的狗屁榮譽更重要…
My bloody honor is beyond repair,
我什麼狗屁榮譽都無法挽回了
but my answer is still no. I don't want Casterly Rock.
但我的答案仍然是「不」，我不想要凱巖城
I don't want a wife. I don't want children.
我不想要妻子，我不想要孩子
What do you want?
你想要什麼？
Supper would be nice.
晚飯就行
For 40 years I've tried to teach you.
40年了，我一直努力教導你
If you haven't learned by now, you never will.
如果你現在還不開竅，那以後也不會了
Go.
去吧
<i>If serving as a glorified</i> <i>bodyguard</i>
<i>如果當個美其名的保鏢</i>
is the sum of your ambition, go serve.
就是你的人生大志，那就當去吧
I suppose you want the sword back.
我想你會要回這把劍
Keep it.
留著吧
A one-handed man with no family needs
沒有家室的獨手男
all the help he can get.
需要多多幫助
How many Dornishmen does it take to fuck a goat?
操一隻羊要幾個多恩人？
Please don't.
拜託別
<i>Seems to me</i> <i>the smart place</i>
<i>我覺得，要接見旅行者</i>
<i>to meet travelers</i> <i>is in a tavern.</i>
<i>最好是在小酒館</i>
That way, one party is late,
這樣的話，錯過一個聚會
the other party can drink some ale inside.
還有別的聚會可以蹭點酒喝
This is the Prince of Dorne we're waiting for,
我們等的是多恩的親王
not one of your sellsword friends.
不是你那些傭兵朋友
If he's so damned important, how come they sent you to meet him?
如果他真特別重要，他們怎麼會派你來接見？
There's bad blood between the Martells of Dorne
多恩的馬泰爾家族
and the Lannisters of Casterly Rock. Has been for years.
與凱巖城的蘭尼斯特家族向來不和
And just in case the Martells of Dorne
所以萬一馬泰爾家族
are looking to spill some Lannister blood,
想放了某個蘭尼斯特的血
- it may as well be yours, eh? - No need for cynicism.
- 還是放你的比較好，是吧？
- 別冷嘲熱諷了
I happen to be an accomplished diplomat.
我正巧是個熟練的外交家
Ah, here we are.
來了
<i>Can you read the sigils?</i>
<i>你認識那些徽章嗎？</i>
Yellow balls?
一堆黃球？
Wild lemons on a purple field,
紫色底色上排列著檸檬
House Dalt of Lemonwood.
檸檬林的達特家族
A vulture grasping a baby in its talons, House Blackmont.
黑色禿鷹爪抓一個嬰孩，布萊蒙家族
A crowned skull, the Manwoodys of Kingsgrave.
帶金冠的白色骷髏，王冢城的曼伍笛家族
Boy knows his Dornish Houses.
這孩子挺瞭解多恩的家族
I need a sigil.
我需要一個徽章
And House Martell, a red sun pierced by a spear?
馬泰爾家族，一柄貫穿紅日的金槍
I don't see it, my lord.
我沒看到，大人
Well met, my lords.
很高興見面，大人們
His Grace King Joffrey welcomes you in his name.
以喬佛裏陛下的名義歡迎您們
My lord father, the King's Hand, sends his greetings as well.
我的父親大人，國王之手也向您們致以問候
I am Tyrion Lannister of Casterly Rock,
我是凱巖城的提利昂·蘭尼斯特
Master of Coin.
財政大臣
Forgive me.
原諒我
I don't see Prince Doran in your company.
我沒有看到道朗親王隨行
The prince's health forces him to remain at Sunspear.
親王身體抱恙，只能留在陽戟城
He sends his brother Prince Oberyn
他派來了他的弟弟奧伯倫親王
<i>to attend the royal</i> <i>wedding in his stead.</i>
<i>來代替他參加皇室婚禮</i>
Yes, the king will be delighted to enjoy the company
好的，國王會很高興能有
of a warrior as renowned as Prince Oberyn
如奧伯倫親王這樣有名望的武士前來
at his wedding feast.
參加他的喜宴
Will he?
是嗎？
And where is Prince Oberyn?
那奧伯倫親王在哪裏？
Arrived before dawn.
黎明前就到了
Not a man for welcome parties,
他不愛參加歡迎儀式
<i>our prince.</i>
<i>我們的親王</i>
Very well. My lords, these fine men from the City Watch
很好，大人們，這些守備隊的精銳護衛
will escort you to your quarters in the Red Keep.
會護送您們到紅堡的住處
You must be weary after such a long journey.
如此長途跋涉您們一定很疲憊了
Some accomplished diplomacy that was.
這就是熟練的外交家
Now where?
現在去哪？
We must find Prince Oberyn before he kills somebody
我們必須在奧伯倫親王殺某人
or several somebodies.
或很多人前找到他
How do you plan on finding a single Dornishman in a city this big?
城市這麼大，你打算怎麼找一個多恩人？
You're famous for fucking half of Westeros.
假設你號稱操過一半維斯特洛人
You just arrived at the capital after two weeks of bad roads,
你剛剛顛簸了兩個星期到達王都
where would you go?
你會去哪？
I'd probably go to sleep, but I'm getting old.
我可能會去睡，不過我老了
Look at this one.
看看這個
How lovely is she?
她多可愛啊？
Beautiful.
真美
But pale.
但是太蒼白
They like them pale in the capital.
王都的人就喜歡蒼白的
Shows they don't work the fields.
說明她們不在外幹活
Do I frighten you?
我嚇著你了？
You like?
你喜歡嗎？
Timid. Timid bores me.
太害羞，害羞的沒意思
You're a bit of mischief, aren't you?
你是個小頑皮，是嗎？
I think she likes you.
我覺得她喜歡你
She has good taste.
她品味不錯啊
You're not timid, are you?
你可一點也不害羞啊
Not timid.
真不害羞
Do you like women?
你喜歡女人？
When they look like her, my lord.
只喜歡她的這樣的，大人
This one will do nicely.
這個會很不錯
<i>Very good, my lady.</i>
<i>非常好，夫人</i>
Oh, I'm not a lady.
我可不是夫人
A term of courtesy in this establishment.
只是這裏的恭維話
A lie anywhere.
在哪說都是謊話
Why not use the right words?
為什麼不直說？
I'm a bastard.
我是個雜種
She is a whore. And you're what?
她是妓女，你是什麼？
A procurer.
拉皮條的
Any of the others?
還要其他人嗎？
The two girls can leave.
這兩個女孩可以走了
You stay.
你留下
I'm afraid I'm not an offer, my lord.
恐怕我不供娛樂，大人
Everyone who works for Littlefinger is an offer.
所有給小指頭當差的都供娛樂
Take off your clothes. We'll be here a while.
把衣服脫了，我們會在這裏待一會
- My lord. - I am a prince, boy.
- 大人
- 我是親王，小子
Have you ever been with a prince?
你跟親王搞過嗎？
Can't say I have.
沒有
I'm wildly expensive.
我身價很高的
Take off your clothes.
把衣服脫了
Which way do you like it?
你想怎麼來？
My way.
按我的方式來
<i>♪ And so he spoke</i> <i>and so he spoke ♪</i>
<i>♪ 他這樣說，他這樣說 ♪</i>
<i>♪ That Lord of Castamere ♪</i>
<i>♪ 卡斯特梅的領主 ♪</i>
- <i>♪ And now the rains... ♪</i> - Oberyn.
- <i>♪ 雨水在大廳哭泣… ♪</i>
- 奧伯倫，不要
<i>♪ With no one there</i> <i>to hear ♪</i>
<i>♪ 內裏卻無人影 ♪</i>
♪ Yes, not the rains weep o'er his hall ♪
♪ 雨水在大廳哭泣 ♪
♪ And not a soul to hear. ♪
♪ 內裏卻無魂靈 ♪
You lost, friend?
你迷路了，朋友？
Forgive me for staring.
很抱歉盯著你們看
I don't see many Lannisters where I'm from.
我們那裏很少有蘭尼斯特家的人
I don't see many Dornishmen in the capital.
我在首都也很少看到多恩人
We don't like the smell.
我們不喜歡這種氣味
- Come with me, lover. - Gods, look at this one.
- 跟我來，親愛的
- 天哪，看看她
Sirs, if you follow me, I'll arrange for a private room.
爵士，跟我來，我為您安排單間
Why are you wasting a woman like this on a Dornishman?
為什麼把這麼一個美人讓多恩人糟蹋？
Bring him a shaved goat and a bottle of olive oil.
給他找頭剃了毛的山羊和橄欖油
Do you know why all the world hates a Lannister?
你知道為什麼全世界都恨蘭尼斯特嗎？
You think your gold and your lions
你們以為你們的金子，獅子
and your gold lions make you better than everyone.
金獅子讓你們高人一等
May I tell you a secret?
我能跟你說個秘密嗎？
You're not a golden lion.
你不是金獅子
You're just a pink little man
你就是個沒用的白人
who is far too slow on the draw.
拔劍遲緩
Longsword is a bad option in close quarters.
長劍在近身戰中不是明智的選擇
When I pull my blade, your friend starts bleeding.
我一拔劍，你的朋友就得流血了
Quite a lot, I'm afraid. So many veins in the wrist.
恐怕會流很多，手腕上有這麼多血管
He'll live if you get him help straightaway.
你立刻幫他，他就能活命
So, decisions.
那麼，決定吧
Prince Oberyn, forgive the intrusion.
奧伯倫王子，原諒我不請自來
We heard there might be...
我們聽說這裏可能會有…
...trouble.
…麻煩
Apologies, my love.
抱歉，親愛的
I'm here to welcome you to the capital.
歡迎你來到首都
Ellaria Sand, my paramour.
艾拉莉亞·沙德，我的情人
The king's own Uncle Imp.
這位是國舅小惡魔
Tyrion, son of Tywin Lannister.
提利昂，泰溫·蘭尼斯特之子
If there's anything I can do to make your stay--
有任何…我可以使你…
What are you? His hired killer?
你是誰？他僱傭的殺手？
It started that way, aye. Now I'm a knight.
那是以前，現在我是騎士
How did that come to pass?
你怎麼做到的？
Killed the right people, I suppose.
殺了該殺的人，我猜
We'll need a few more girls. Girls, yes?
我們還需要一些姑娘，行嗎？
You don't partake?
你不一起來？
Oh, I partook. Now I'm married.
以前來過，現在我結婚了
Prince Oberyn, if I may, a word in private?
奧伯倫王子，我們能否單獨談談？
Seems I visited the Lannister brothel by mistake.
看樣子我不該來蘭尼斯特的妓院
- Oh, they take all kinds. - Even Dornishmen.
- 他們接待各種客人
- 包括多恩人
The king is very grateful that you traveled all
國王對你遠道而來參加他的婚禮
this way for his wedding.
十分感激
Let us speak truth here. Joffrey is insulted.
說實話吧，喬佛裏受恥辱了
I am only the second son after all.
畢竟我只是次子
Well, speaking as a fellow second son,
同樣作為次子
I have grown rather used to being the family insult.
我打小就是家族的恥辱
Why did you come to King's Landing, Prince Oberyn?
你為何來君臨城，奧伯倫親王？
I was invited to the royal wedding.
我受邀參加王室婚禮
I thought we were speaking truth.
我以為我們在開誠佈公地談
The last time I was in the capital was many years ago.
我上次來首都是好多年前了
Another wedding.
另一場婚禮
My sister Elia
我妹妹伊莉亞
and Rhaegar Targaryen, the Last Dragon.
和雷加·坦格利安，最後的真龍
My sister loved him. She bore his children.
我妹妹愛他，為他生了孩子
Swaddled them, rocked them, fed them at her own breast.
抱他們，哄他們，親自哺乳
Elia wouldn't let the wet nurse touch them.
伊莉亞不讓奶媽碰他們
And beautiful, noble Rhaegar Targaryen
美麗尊貴的雷加·坦格利安
left her for another woman.
卻為了另一個女人離開了她
That started a war
挑起一場戰爭
and the war ended right here
那場戰爭就結束於此地
when your father's army took the city...
你父親的軍隊攻下了這座城…
I wasn't actually present.
我當時不在
...and butchered those children.
…殘殺了那些孩子
My nephew and niece.
我的侄子侄女
Carved them up and wrapped them in Lannister cloaks.
他們被切碎包在蘭尼斯特的斗篷裏
And my sister, you know what they did to her?
至於我妹妹，你知道他們對她做了什麼嗎？
I'm asking you a question.
我在問你
I've heard rumors.
我聽到過傳言
So have I.
我也是
The one I keep hearing is that Gregor Clegane the Mountain
我聽到的是魔山格雷果·克裏岡
raped Elia and split her in half
強姦了伊利亞，用他的劍
with his great sword.
把她劈成兩半
I wasn't there. I don't know what happened.
我不在場，不知道發生了什麼
If the Mountain killed my sister,
如果魔山殺了我妹妹
your father gave the order.
就是你父親下的令
Tell your father I'm here.
告訴你父親我來了
And tell him the Lannisters aren't the only ones who pay their debts.
告訴他不是只有蘭尼斯特家的人有債必償
Shh.
噓
Shh. Shh.
噓，噓
They're dragons, Khaleesi.
它們是龍，卡麗熙
They can never be tamed.
無法被馴服
Not even by their mother.
即使是它們的母親
- Ser Barristan. - Your Grace.
- 巴利斯坦爵士
- 女王陛下
Where's Daario Naharis?
達裏奧·納哈里斯在哪？
Where's Grey Worm?
灰蟲子在哪？
Gambling, Your Grace.
賭博，陛下
Gambling?
賭博？
Mhysa. Mhysa. Mhysa...
彌莎，彌莎，彌莎…
How long have they been at it?
他們僵持多久了？
Since midnight, Your Grace.
半夜就開始了，陛下
Ser Worm is stronger than he looks.
蠕蟲爵士比他看起來強壯
But I can see his arms beginning to shake.
但我能看出來他的手開始抖了
What's the prize to winning this stupid contest?
這場愚蠢的比賽獎品是什麼？
The honor of riding by your side on the road to Meereen.
去彌林的路上跟您並駕而驅的榮耀
That honor goes to Ser Jorah and Ser Barristan
這榮耀屬於喬拉爵士和巴利斯坦爵士
as neither of them kept me waiting this morning.
因為今早他們沒有讓我等
You two will ride in the rear guard and protect the livestock.
你們倆作後衛保護輜重
The last man holding his sword
最後一個拿劍的人
can find a new queen to fight for.
可以另尋明主了
你喜歡這個女孩？
很受挫吧
你不夠聰明，達裏奧·奧哈里斯
我寧願自己沒腦子
有兩個蛋
You need to eat something.
你得吃點東西
Pigeon pie.
鴿子派
No, thank you.
不用，謝謝
Lemon cakes?
檸檬蛋糕？
No, thank you.
不用，謝謝
You love lemon cakes.
你愛吃檸檬蛋糕啊
Tell her she needs to eat.
跟她說她得吃點東西
My lady, you do need to eat.
小姐，你真的得吃點
I don't need to eat.
我不想吃
If I could have a moment alone with my wife.
請容我與我妻子獨處一會
She needs to eat.
她得吃點東西
I can't let you starve.
我不能讓你餓死
<i>I swore to protect you.</i>
<i>我發過誓會保護你</i>
My lady,
小姐
I am your husband. Let me help you.
我是你丈夫，讓我來幫你
How can you help me?
你怎麼幫我？
I don't know, but I can try.
我不知道，但我可以試試
I lie awake all night staring at the canopy
我整夜未眠盯著房頂
thinking about how they died.
想著他們如何死去
I could get you essence of nightshade to help you sleep.
我可以給你夜影之水幫助你入眠
Do you know what they did to my brother?
你知道他們對我哥哥做了什麼嗎？
How they sewed his direwolf's head onto his body?
他們怎麼把冰原狼的頭縫到他身上？
And my mother.
還有我母親
They say they cut her throat to the bone
他們說他們割斷她的喉嚨
and threw her body in the river.
把她的遺體丟進河裏
<i>What happened to your family</i> <i>was a terrible crime.</i>
<i>你們家族的遭遇</i><i>是很可怕的罪行</i>
I didn't know your brother.
我不瞭解你哥哥
He seemed like a good man, but I didn't know him.
他看上去是個好人，但我不瞭解他
<i>Your mother,</i> <i>on the other hand,</i>
<i>你母親則不然</i>
<i>I admired her.</i>
<i>我敬仰她</i>
She wanted to have me executed,
她想處死我
but I admired her.
但我敬仰她
She was a strong woman.
她是個堅強的女人
And she was fierce
在保護她的孩子時
when it came to protecting her children.
她又可以很兇殘
Sansa.
珊莎
Your mother would want you to carry on.
你母親會希望你向前看
You know it's true.
你知道的
Will you pardon me, my lord?
失陪了，大人
I'd like to visit the godswood.
我想去神木林
Of course. Of course. Prayer can be helpful, I hear.
當然，聽說做禱告會好一點
I don't pray anymore.
我不做禱告了
It's the only place I can go where people don't talk to me.
我不想聽別人說話只能去那裏了
My lion.
我的獅子
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
What does it look like I'm doing? Come here.
我看起來像在做什麼？過來
How many times have I told you? You can't visit me here.
我跟你說過多少次了？你不能到這來找我
I know. I know.
我知道，我知道
We have come to a dangerous place.
我們身處險境
Have you forgotten me? Do you know how long it's been?
你忘記我了嗎？你知道過了多久了嗎？
Of course I haven't forgotten.
當然，我沒忘記
I want you.
我想要你
Don't you want me?
你不想要我嗎？
Things are a bit tense right now.
現在情勢有點緊張
What things?
什麼情勢？
My nephew the king wants to murder me.
我侄子，國王想殺我
My wife hates me because my father murdered her family.
我妻子恨我，因為我父親謀殺她整個家族
Oberyn Martell wants to murder everyone whose
奧柏倫馬泰爾想殺了所有
last name is Lannister.
蘭尼斯特家族的人
You need to relax.
你需要放鬆
Don't you want to relax?
你不想好好放鬆一下？
- What's wrong? - I told you.
- 到底怎麼了？
- 我說了
- It's not a good time. - It's never a good time.
- 現在不合適
- 永遠都不合適
- You have your child bride now. - Shae.
- 現在你有那個小姑娘當老婆了
- 雪伊
- Do you love her? - Love her?
- 你愛她嗎？
- 愛？
I barely know her. She's a child.
我都不怎麼瞭解她，她只是個小孩
- She despises me. - That's not an answer.
- 她看不起我
- 這不算回答
Of course I don't love her.
我當然不愛她
You tried to ship me away.
你想派船把我送走
Ship you away?
送走你？
Give me diamonds and make me disappear.
給我鑽石然後讓我永遠消失
What in the world are you talking about?
你到底在說什麼
If you want me to leave, just say it.
如果你想讓我走，說一聲就行了
- Say it! - Shh.
- 說啊！
- 噓
I don't know what you're talking about.
我真的不知道你在說些什麼
You want me to stay?
那你想讓我留下？
A work of art, really.
真是件藝術品
The craftsmanship is excellent.
這手藝可真精妙
You like it so much,
既然你這麼喜歡
you're welcome to chop off your own hand and take it.
不如把自己手剁了然後拿去用
Such an ingrate. I spent days with the goldsmith
真忘恩負義，我和金匠花了好幾天
- getting the details just right. - Days?
- 才把細節做得這麼恰到好處
- 幾天？
Better part of an afternoon.
都是下午
There, how does that feel?
好了，感覺怎麼樣？
Uh...
呃…
a hook would be more practical.
如果是鉤子的話更實用
Elegant, I think.
我覺這個更優雅
Thank you for your help with the other matter.
其它的事情也謝謝你幫忙了
- The symptoms have abated? - Gone completely.
- 癥狀緩和了嗎？
- 已經都好了
I am in your debt, Maester Qyburn.
科本學士，我欠你人情
Not a maester, Your Grace, but happy to help
不是學士了，夫人，但只要我能幫忙
whenever I can.
任何時候都樂意效勞
Odd little man.
怪人
I've grown rather fond of him.
我越來越喜歡他了
He's quite talented, you know?
你知道嗎，他很有才能
What symptoms?
哪些方面
Symptoms that are not your concern.
都是些你不關心的
You let him touch you?
你讓他摸你了？
You jealous?
你嫉妒了？
I'm surprised.
只是驚訝
You never let Pycelle near you.
你沒讓派席爾近過身
You think I'd let that old lecher put his hands on me?
你覺得我會讓那個老色鬼碰我？
He smells like a dead cat.
他的味道像死貓
<i>I'm not sure I've ever</i> <i>smelled a dead cat.</i>
我不確定我有沒有聞過死貓
Well, they smell like Pycelle.
它們聞起來和派席爾一樣
You drink more than you used to.
你喝酒比原來多了
- Yes. - Why?
- 沒錯
- 為什麼？
Let's see, you started a brawl in the streets with Ned Stark
為什麼？你在街上襲擊奈德·史塔克
and disappeared from the capital.
然後從君臨消失
My husband died in a tragic hunting accident.
我丈夫死於悲慘的打獵事故
It must have been traumatic for you.
你一定深受重創
My only daughter was shipped off to Dorne.
我唯一的女兒被船送去了多恩
<i>We suffered</i> <i>through a siege.</i>
我們被人圍攻
A rather short siege.
短暫的圍攻
A rather short siege that I didn't expect to survive.
真短，短到我都沒想過能活下來
And now I'm marrying my eldest son
現在我要讓長子
to a wicked little bitch from Highgarden
和從高庭來的邪惡的小婊子結婚
while I'm supposed to marry her brother,
我還被許配給了她哥哥
a renowned pillow biter. So...
公認的騙子，所以…
Father disowned me today.
爸已經不認我了
He can't disown you. You're all he's got.
他不能不認你，你是他的全部
You're forgetting Tyrion.
你忘了提利昂
You don't really plan on staying in the Kingsguard, do you?
你不會真想留在御林鐵衛，對吧？
Staying in the Kingsguard means I live right here
留在御林鐵衛意味著我能在這裏
in the Red Keep with you.
在紅堡陪你
- Not now. - I want--
- 現在不行
- 我想要
Not now? When? I've been back for weeks.
現在不行，那什麼時候行？我已經回來幾個星期了
- Something's changed. - Everything's changed.
- 有些事情變了
- 所有事情都變了
You come back after all this time with no apologies
你這麼久才回來，還折了一隻手
and one hand and expect everything to be the same?
連一聲道歉都沒有，還希望一切和原來一樣？
What do you want me to apologize for?
你想讓我為什麼道歉？
For leaving me.
為離開我
You think I wanted to be taken prisoner?
你以為我想做囚犯？
Don't know what you wanted. You weren't here.
我不知道你想要什麼，總之你不在這裏
You left me alone.
你拋下我一個人
Every day I was a prisoner, I plotted my escape.
我在外面當著囚犯，每天都謀劃著逃出來
Every day. I murdered people so I could be here with you.
我殺了人才能在這裏和你相見
- You took too long. - I...
- 太久了
- 我…
- What are you saying? - I'm saying you took too long.
- 你到底在說什麼？
- 我說你去了太久
- Come in. <i>- Go away.</i>
- 進來
- 出去
Forgive me, Your Grace.
抱歉，夫人
You told me to come at once if there was anything important.
您說如果有緊急事態就讓我馬上來
You plan on killing all the crows yourself?
你想單槍匹馬殺了所有烏鴉？
Do you plan on sitting here scratching your balls till winter?
那你就一直坐那兒抓你的蛋蛋抓到冬天？
We wait for Mance's orders.
我們在等曼斯的命令
You sent a man over the Wall at the full moon.
滿月時你派了一個人去長城
<i>If he's not back yet,</i> <i>he's not coming back.</i>
如果他還沒回來那他就回不來了
<i>And what is it</i> <i>you want?</i>
你到底想要做什麼？
March on Castle Black with just this lot?
帶著這點人就想朝黑城堡進軍？
Your pretty crow said 1,000 men are nesting there.
你那可愛的烏鴉說那兒有一千人駐守
Yeah, well, he's a liar.
他是個騙子
He is?
他是？
Shouldn't it be "he was"?
難道不應該是「他原來是」？
You said you put three arrows in him.
你說向他射了三支箭
I did.
沒錯
I've seen you slip a shaft through a rabbit's eye at 200 yards.
我曾見你把箭射進兩百碼外的兔子的眼睛
If that boy's still walking, it's 'cause you let him go.
如果他還能走，那是你放他走的
Thenns.
塞恩人
I fucking hate Thenns.
我真他媽討厭塞恩人
Mance sent you?
曼斯讓你們來的？
How did you find us?
你們怎麼找到我們的？
You came from the south, not the north.
你們從南邊來，不是北邊
Took a detour.
我們繞了點路
Got some supper from a village down that way.
在路上的村子弄了點晚餐
<i>Why does the meat down here</i> <i>taste so much better</i>
為什麼長城這邊的肉…
than it does on our side of the Wall?
比我們那邊的更好吃？
Help yourself.
請自便
Maybe everything's just better fed down here.
可能這裏的東西都被餵養的挺好
Fat and lazy.
又胖又懶
Easier for us, hmm?
對我們來說容易多了，不是嗎？
You didn't see us coming?
你們沒看到我們過來？
Lost your warg?
你們的狼靈丟了？
And that baby crow you had with you,
還有你們的小烏鴉
lost him too?
也丟了？
I'll answer to Mance.
我只聽從曼斯
I won't answer to you.
不聽從你
She yours?
她是你的？
I'm not anybody's.
我不是任何人的
Too scrawny.
真瘦
Not like those crows at Castle Black.
不像黑城堡的那些烏鴉
<i>Think of them</i> <i>stuck in their larders</i>
想想他們被卡在儲藏間裏
stuffing their faces with ham and blood sausage
香腸和火腿吃的滿臉都是
and stew, getting nice and fat
還能燉東西吃，變得又白又胖
and marbled.
長的五花肉
I know we've had our differences, Tormund,
我知道我們有些不同，托蒙德
but just one time before you die,
但在你死之前，你真的要嘗嘗烏鴉
you really ought to try crow.
就這一次
<i>Draw.</i>
拉箭
Loose.
放箭
<i>Last time I saw him,</i>
我最後一次見到他
<i>he was in the courtyard</i> <i>at Winterfell.</i>
是在臨冬城的院子裏
<i>He said,</i> <i>"Next time I see you,</i>
他說，下次我再見到你
<i>you'll be all in black."</i>
你就是守夜人了
I was jealous of Robb my whole life.
我一輩子都嫉妒羅柏
<i>The way my father</i> <i>looked at him,</i>
父親看他的樣子
<i>I wanted that.</i>
我嫉妒
He was better than me at everything--
他什麼都比我強
fighting and hunting
戰鬥，打獵
and riding
騎馬
and girls.
還有姑娘們
<i>Gods, the girls</i> <i>loved him.</i>
諸神啊，女孩們都喜歡他
I wanted to hate him, but I never could.
我想恨他，但我做不到
Sometimes I want to hate you.
有的時候，我想要恨你
Well, you're better than me at everything.
嗯，你什麼都比我強
Except reading.
讀書除外
They're-- they're ready for you.
他們…他們在等著你
He's wanted to hang me for a while. Now's his chance.
他一直想絞死我，現在機會來了
No one's going to hang you.
沒人想絞死你
You've done nothing wrong.
你沒做錯任何事
I've done plenty wrong.
我的錯太多了
So you admit you murdered Qhorin Halfhand?
所以你承認你謀殺了斷掌科林
<i>I didn't murder him.</i>
不是謀殺
No? You put your sword
不是？你把你的劍…
through a brother of the Night's Watch.
揮向了守夜人兄弟
What do you call that?
你說說那是什麼？
He wanted me to kill him.
他希望我殺死他
A bastard son of a traitor.
對背叛者的私生子
What would you expect?
你還能期待什麼
The Halfhand believed our only chance
科林堅信，我們抵擋住曼斯的唯一機會
to stop Mance was to get a man inside his army.
就是在他的軍隊裏安插一個人
Don't talk about the Halfhand as if you knew him.
不要這樣說話，好像你很瞭解他
He was my brother.
他曾經是我兄弟
Then you'd know he'd do anything to defend the Wall.
那你應該知道為了鎮守長城他會做任何事
The free folk would have boiled him alive, but letting me kill him...
自由民本可活活煮死他，但讓我動手殺死他
<i>The free folk?</i> <i>Listen to him.</i>
- 自由民？
- 聽聽
He even talks like a wildling now.
他連說話都像個野人
Aye, I talk like a wildling. I ate with the wildlings.
是的，我像野人一樣說話，我與野人一同吃飯
I climbed the Wall with the wildlings. I--
我與野人一同爬過長城
I laid with a wildling girl.
我…我還睡了一個野人姑娘
You admit to breaking your vows, then?
那你承認違背誓言了？
I do.
是的
The law is the law. The boy must die.
規矩就是規矩，這個小子必須死
If we beheaded every ranger who lay with a girl,
如果每一個與姑娘上床的游騎兵都得被砍頭
the Wall would be manned by headless men.
守長城的就都是些無頭者了
There's a difference between sneaking off
溜進鼴鼠城的妓院和與敵人上床
to the Mole's Town brothel and sleeping with the enemy.
這是不一樣的
While we sit here
就在此時，我們坐在這裏
debating which rules I broke,
爭論我到底犯了哪一條規矩
Mance Rayder marches on the Wall with an army of 100,000.
曼斯·雷德正帶著十萬人的軍隊行進在長城上
Impossible.
這不可能
You can't get 50 wildlings together
哪怕有50個野人聚集起來
before they start killing each other.
他們就開始自相殘殺了
100,000. He's united the Thenns,
有十萬人，他聯合了瑟恩人
<i>the Hornfoots,</i> <i>the ice-river clans.</i>
<i>霍恩福特人,和冰河族人</i>
He has giants fighting for him.
巨人也為他作戰
Giants?
巨人？
Have you ever been beyond the Wall, ser?
你去過長城外面嗎，長官？
I commanded the City Watch of King's Landing, boy.
我可是君臨都城守備隊的指揮，小子
And now you're here.
可你現在在這兒
You must not have been very good at your job.
那你一定幹得不好
How dare you?!
你竟敢口出狂言？！
There's a band of wildlings south of the Wall already
已經有一小隊野人到了長城南面
led by Tormund Giantsbane.
是「巨人剋星托蒙德」帶的隊
I killed their warg and three others.
我殺了他們的狼靈和三名野人
They shot me full of arrows.
他們朝我射了一大把箭
Their orders are to attack Castle Black from the south
他們的任務是從南側進攻黑城堡
when Mance hits it from the north.
曼斯則從北面進攻
The signal for the attack will be a bonfire.
進攻的信號就是篝火
Mance said it would be the greatest fire the North has ever seen.
曼斯說，這將是北方人見過最壯麗的篝火
<i>That's the truth.</i>
<i>這是實話</i>
All the truth.
都是實話
Do you intend to execute me or am I free to go?
你們要處決我，還是還我自由？
None of us are free.
這兒沒人是自由的
We are men of the Night's Watch.
我們是守夜人
But we won't be taking your head today, Jon Snow.
但我們今天不會取你的腦袋，瓊恩·雪諾
Go on.
走吧
I am acting commander here, Maester Aemon.
我才是這裏的執行官，伊蒙學士
Yes, you are.
是的，你才是
And I don't trust the bastard.
我不信任這個私生子
He told the truth.
他說的是實話
And you always know when a man's telling a lie?
只要有人說謊，你都能辨別出來嗎？
How did you acquire this magical power?
你這魔法是從哪兒學來的？
I grew up in King's Landing.
我可是在君臨城長大的
<i>No. No.</i>
<i>不行，不行</i>
You're a queen, not an ox.
你可是皇后，又不是公牛
Your grandfather gave me a necklace
你爺爺曾送給我一條項鏈，跟這個一樣
just like this one for my 51st nameday.
在我第51個命名日上
The wedding is in a fortnight, Grandmother.
兩周後就要舉行婚禮了，奶奶
You can't say no to everything.
你不能對所有事情都不滿意
Nonsense. My little dears.
胡說！我的小寶貝
Go and speak to the jewelers of King's Landing.
去找君臨城的珠寶匠
Tell them who you are, tell them who sent you.
告訴他們你們是誰，是誰派你們來的
The one who brings me the best necklace
誰找到最好的項鏈
will get to keep the next best.
就能得到第二好的那一條
The Margaery Tyrell who walks into the sept
瑪格麗特·提利爾兩周後要大婚
a fortnight from now will inspire 1,000 songs.
將會給上千首歌帶來靈感
Now, how sad it will be if she's wearing rubbish like that.
要是她戴著這樣的垃圾貨色，該有多傷心
Perhaps I should just let Joffrey choose it for me.
也許我就該讓喬佛裏給我挑選一條
End up with a string of dead sparrow heads around my neck.
最後肯定是戴一串死麻雀的腦袋在脖子上
You watch that. Even here, even with me.
你瞧好了，他要是敢在這兒，在我面前這麼做
My word.
我的天哪
My lady. My lady.
老夫人，小姐
Please pardon me for interrupting.
抱歉打擾了
My name is Brienne of Tarth.
我是塔斯的布蕾妮
We know who you are. We've heard all about you.
我們知道你是誰，久仰大名
But hearing is one thing.
但是耳聽為虛
Aren't you just marvelous?
你真是太棒了
Absolutely singular.
絕對獨一無二
I hear you knocked my grandson into the dirt
我聽說你把我孫子打昏在地
like the silly little boy he is.
就好像他是個笨小孩
My lady, I know this is a very busy time for you,
小姐，我知道您現在非常忙
but if I could just have a moment.
但是能允許我耽誤您一會兒嗎？
You dare not refuse.
你怎能拒絕呢
A shadow?
影子？
A shadow with the face of Stannis Baratheon.
一個影子長著史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩的臉
I swear to you by all the gods it was Stannis.
我以諸神的名義向您發誓，那是史坦尼斯
He plunged his sword through Renly's heart
他把他的劍插進藍禮的心臟
and disappeared.
然後就消失了
One day, my lady, I will avenge our king.
小姐，總有一天我會為我們的國王報仇
Joffrey is our king now.
現在喬佛裏是我們的國王
I meant no offense.
我並無冒犯之意
And you've given none.
你並未冒犯
All the Kingsguard will be on duty, of course.
當然，所有御林鐵衛都必須到位
Ser Boros will be stationed here.
柏洛斯爵士的崗位在這兒
Ser Preston will be stationed here
普萊斯特爵士的崗位在這兒
beside the primary entertainment.
在主樂隊旁邊
Your Grace?
陛下？
Yes, yes, one guard at the--
是的，可以，一個守衛，在…
the thing. Go on.
在那個地方，你們繼續
Ser Meryn will guard Lady Margaery and Tommen.
馬林爵士保護瑪格麗特小姐和托曼
I've always guarded the king himself, my lord.
大人，我一直親自保護國王
Ever since your absence.
在你離開的這段時間裏
And I thank you for it, Ser Meryn.
為此我非常感謝，馬林爵士
All very good. I don't expect any trouble.
非常好，我可不想有什麼麻煩
The people love their king.
人們愛戴他們的國王
They know who keeps them fed.
他們知道是誰讓他們填飽肚子
Margaery Tyrell, I've heard.
我聽說是瑪格麗特·提利爾
By my leave.
當我不在的時候
They know I saved the city. They know I won the war.
他們知道是我拯救了這座城市，是我贏得了戰爭
The war's not won. Not while Stannis lives.
只要史坦尼斯還活著，戰爭就還未勝利
I broke Stannis on the Blackwater.
我在黑水河之役擊敗了史坦尼斯
Pity you weren't there to help, Uncle.
可惜你不在那兒，幫不上忙，舅舅
My apologies, Your Grace. I was rather busy.
抱歉，陛下，我當時很忙
Busy getting captured.
忙著被抓呢
So this is the famous "Book of Brothers"?
這就是有名的「鐵衛名冊」？
All the great deeds of all the great Kingsguard.
御林鐵衛的英雄事跡
Ser Arthur Dayne. The Sword of the Morning.
亞瑟·戴恩爵士，拂曉神劍
Led the attack on the Kingswood Brotherhood.
帶領剿滅御林兄弟會
Defeated the Smiling Knight in single combat.
在決戰中擊敗了微笑騎士
Ser Duncan the Tall.
高個鄧肯爵士
Four pages for Ser Duncan.
鄧肯爵士的事跡寫了四頁呢
He must have been quite a man.
他一定是個勇士
So they say.
他們是這麼說
Ser Jaime Lannister.
詹姆·蘭尼斯特爵士
Someone forgot to write down all your great deeds.
有人忘了把你的英雄事跡寫上
- There's still time. - Is there?
- 來日方長
- 是嗎？
For a 40-year-old knight with one hand?
四十歲的獨臂騎士？
How can you protect me with that?
你這樣還怎麼保護我？
I use my left hand now, Your Grace.
我現在可以用左手，陛下
Makes for more of a contest.
更有競爭力
Have you ever been to Meereen?
你去過彌林嗎？
Several times, Your Grace, with Master Kraznys.
去過幾次，陛下，和克拉茲尼一起
And?
然後呢？
They say 1,000 slaves died
他們說在建造彌林大金字塔時
building the Great Pyramid of Meereen.
死了一千名奴隸
And now an army of former slaves
而現在，一支由之前的奴隸組成的軍隊
is marching to her gates.
正在向她的大門行進
You think the Great Masters are worried?
你覺得偉主們會擔心嗎？
If they're smart, Your Grace.
如果他們聰明的話，陛下
You were told to ride at the back of the train.
你應該跟在隊伍的最後
Yes, my queen.
是的，我的女王
But I need to speak to you about something important.
但是我有重要的事情要對您說
A matter of strategy.
戰略事務
Your Grace.
陛下
All right, what is this matter of strategy?
好吧，什麼戰略事務？
A dusk rose.
一支幽暗玫瑰
Would you like to walk at the back of the train instead of riding?
你是想在隊伍最後跟著走嗎？而不是騎馬
And this one's called lady's lace.
這一支叫做女人的蕾絲
Would you like to walk without shoes?
你是想光腳走嗎？
You have to know a land to rule it.
您應該瞭解要統治的地方
Its plants, its rivers,
那兒的植物，那兒的河流
its roads, its people.
那兒的道路，那兒的人民
Dusk rose tea eases fever.
幽暗玫瑰茶可以退燒
Everyone in Meereen knows that.
彌林的每個人都知道
Especially the slaves who have to make the tea.
尤其是要沏茶的奴隸
If you want them to follow you,
如果您希望他們跟隨您
you have to become a part of their world.
您就要融入他們的世界
Strategy.
這就是戰略
Harpy's Gold.
金鷹妖
No tea from this one.
這種花不能用來泡茶
Beautiful but poisonous.
美麗但有毒
You are a gambler, aren't you?
你確實是個賭徒，不是嗎？
Your Grace.
陛下
There's one on every mile marker between here and Meereen.
從這兒到彌林每隔一里就有一個
How many miles are there between here and Meereen?
這裏到彌林有多少里？
163, Your Grace.
163里，陛下
<i>I'll tell our men to ride</i> <i>ahead and bury them.</i>
<i>我會下令讓人騎在前面，燒了她們</i>
You don't need to see this.
您不需要看到
You will do no such thing.
不能這麼做
I will see each and every one of their faces.
我要看到她們每一個人的臉
Remove her collar before you bury her.
拿掉項圈，然後把她埋了
<i>There she is.</i>
<i>她在那兒</i>
Yes, there she is.
是的，她在那兒
- And? - You made a promise.
- 然後呢？
- 你保證過的
To return the Stark girls to their mother who is now dead.
把史塔克家的女兒還給她們死了的母親
To keep them safe.
保證她們安全
Well, Arya Stark hasn't been seen since her father was killed.
自從艾莉亞·史塔克的父親死後，再沒人看見過她
Where do you think she is? My money's on dead.
你認為她在哪？我賭她已經死了
There's a certain safety in death, wouldn't you say?
死了也是種安全，你覺得呢？
And Sansa Stark is now Sansa Lannister.
珊莎·史塔克現在叫珊莎·蘭尼斯特
Bit of a complication.
有點複雜
A complication does not release you from a vow.
再複雜也不能言而無信
What do you want me to do? Kidnap my sister-in-law?
你想要我怎樣？綁架我的弟媳？
And take her where? Where would she be safer than here?
然後帶她去哪？哪裏會比這裏安全？
Look me in the eye and tell me
看著我的眼睛告訴我…
that you think she'll be safe in King's Landing.
你認為她在君臨會安全
Are you sure we're not related?
你確定…我們不是親戚？
Ever since I've returned, every Lannister I've seen
自從我回來，我見到的每個蘭尼斯特…
has been a miserable pain in my ass.
都在給我找麻煩
Maybe you're a Lannister, too.
也許你也是其中之一
You've got the hair for it if not the looks.
頭髮很像，樣子差遠了
It's all right.
沒事的
It's all right. It's all right.
沒事的，沒事的
- You're drunk. - Yes.
- 你醉了
- 是的
I have good reason to be.
我喝醉是應該的
Once I was a knight. Now I'm only a fool.
我曾經是騎士，現在只是個弄臣
Don't you know me?
你不認識我？
Ser Dontos. The king's nameday celebration.
唐托斯爵士，在國王的命名日
I'm sorry. I should have remembered.
抱歉，我應該記得的
I can't accept your apology.
你不必道歉
I may be a fool, but I'm a living fool, thanks to you.
也許我是個小丑，但起碼活著，謝謝你
Anyone would have done the same.
每個人都會這麼做的
But only you did.
但只有你
I can never repay you.
我無法報答你
You gave me my life. But this,
我的命是你給的，但這個…
this is worth more than my life.
這個比我的命值錢
It belonged to my mother and her mother before her.
它曾經屬於我的母親，我母親的母親
House Hollard was strong once.
霍拉德家族曾經輝煌過
House on the rise.
崛起的家族
That's all that's left of those days,
但往昔只留下這個…
thanks to a few sad, fat drunks like me.
歸功於幾個像我一樣可悲的酒鬼
I can't take it.
我不能收
It's very, very kind of you, but I can't.
非常非常感謝你，但我不能收
I don't have anything else left.
我沒有別的東西了
That's all.
只有這個
Take it. Wear it.
收下吧，戴上它
Let my name have one more moment in the sun
讓我的名字還能見到陽光
before it disappears from the world.
趁它還沒有消失
I'll wear it with pride, Ser Dontos.
我會驕傲地戴著的，唐托斯爵士
Yeah.
行
<i>When am I going to get</i> <i>a horse of my own?</i>
<i>我什麼時候才能有自己的馬？</i>
The little lady wants a pony.
小女士想要匹馬
The little lady wants away from your stench.
小女士想要遠離你的臭味
Horses aren't easy to come by.
馬可沒那麼容易搞到
Even if they were,
就算有…
you think I'm gonna put you on your own horse?
你以為我會讓你自己騎？
Watch the only thing of value I've got in the world ride away?
讓我唯一有價值的東西逃走？
Why don't you have any money?
你為什麼沒有錢？
Didn't you steal anything from Joffrey before you left?
你離開前不是偷了喬佛裏的東西的？
No.
沒有
You're not very smart, are you?
你不是很機靈，是嗎？
I'm not a thief.
我不是小偷
You're fine with murdering little boys,
你殺小孩子沒事…
but thieving is beneath you?
偷東西卻不行？
A man's got to have a code.
做人要有原則
You think I'm gonna escape?
你以為我會逃走？
Where would I go?
我能去哪？
I'd be dead by nightfall without you.
沒有你，天一黑我就沒命了
My family's gone. I've got no one.
我的家族沒了，我沒人可以依靠
You've got an aunt in the Vale.
你在谷地還有個姨媽
Your rich Aunt Lysa. After I sell you to her,
你富有的萊莎姨媽，我把你賣給她
maybe she'll have enough left over
也許她還剩點錢…
to buy you that pony you want so much.
給你買匹你渴望的馬
<i>I'm hungry.</i> <i>You're hungry.</i>
<i>我餓了，你也餓了</i>
Five horses, five men.
五匹馬，五個人
More than I feel like killing on an empty stomach.
空著肚子，我殺不了這麼多
I know him.
我認識他
<i>The small one.</i> <i>His name is Polliver.</i>
<i>那個小個子，他叫波利佛</i>
He captured us and took us to Harrenhal.
他抓住了我們，帶我們去了赫倫堡
He killed Lommy.
他殺了羅米
What the fuck's a Lommy?
羅米他媽是誰？
He was my friend.
他是我朋友
Polliver stole my sword and put it right through his neck.
波利佛偷了我的劍，刺穿了他的脖子
He's still got it.
他還帶著
<i>Got what?</i>
<i>帶著什麼？</i>
My sword Needle.
我的劍，縫衣針
Needle? Of course you named your sword.
縫衣針？一定是你命名的
Lots of people name their swords.
很多人都給自己的劍命名
Lots of cunts.
很多傻子
What are you-- get back here.
你在干…快回來
My brother gave me that sword.
這劍是我哥哥給的
- Get back here. - He killed my friend.
- 快回來
- 他殺了我朋友
I don't care if he ate your friend.
他吃了你朋友我也不管
We're not going in there.
我們不要進去
<i>Come on, give it up.</i>
<i>過來，你就從了吧</i>
Come here.
過來
- Let's have a feel there. - Leave it.
- 讓我摸摸那裏
- 等下
Come here.
過來
Please, she's a good girl.
求你了，她是好姑娘
Shut your mouth and pour us more ale
閉嘴，給我們倒酒
and we may not take her with us when we're done with her.
我們搞完了，興許把她留下
I know you.
我認識你
You're the Hound.
你是獵狗
<i>Pour our new friend</i> <i>some ale.</i>
<i>給我們的新朋友倒點酒</i>
What brings you so far north?
什麼風把你吹到這麼北的地方？
I could ask the same of you.
我還想問你呢
What are you doing up here?
你在這裏幹嘛？
Just keeping the king's peace.
維持王國的和平
No need. The war's over.
沒必要，戰爭結束了
So I've heard. Stannis defeated at the Blackwater.
我聽說了，史坦尼斯在黑水河被擊潰
Robb Stark killed at the Twins.
羅柏·史塔克在孿河城被殺
And where am I for all of it?
我在幹嘛？
Stuck with your brother.
跟你哥哥混在一起
- Meaning no offense. - None taken.
- 我沒有惡意
- 沒關係
He's good, the Mountain is.
他不錯，我說魔山
Best at what he does.
頂尖高手
But torture, torture, torture, torture.
但就是酷刑、酷刑、酷刑、酷刑
<i>You spend enough time putting</i> <i>the hammer to people,</i>
<i>老用錘子去打人…</i>
<i>you start to feel like</i> <i>a carpenter making chairs.</i>
<i>你會感覺像個木匠在做椅子</i>
Drains the fun right out of it.
毫無樂趣可言
And what's life without a little fun?
沒樂趣幹嘛還活著？
But I don't need to tell you that, eh?
這一點不用我說
She's all right. I've had better.
她還可以，我有過更好的
You know what?
你知道嗎？
You should come with us.
你該跟我們一起走
His kind, they've always got something hidden away somewhere.
他這種人，總是藏了些東西
Gold, silver, more daughters.
金子，銀子，女兒
<i>Always something if you</i> <i>know how to make them talk.</i>
<i>只要讓他們開口，總有些東西</i>
And there's plenty of him between here and King's Landing.
從這裏到君臨城有很多這樣的人
You could do well for yourself.
你可以發筆小財
We certainly have been.
我們已經發了
I'm not going to King's Landing.
我不去君臨城
Think about it. We could do whatever we like
想想吧，我們可以為所欲為
wherever we go.
暢通無阻
These are the king's colors.
這是國王的顏色
No one's standing in his way now.
沒人敢反抗他
Which means no one's standing in ours.
也就是說，沒人敢反抗我們
Fuck the king.
操國王他媽
When I heard that Joffrey's dog had tucked tail
我聽說喬佛裏的狗夾著尾巴…
and run from the Battle of the Blackwater,
逃離了黑水河之戰
I didn't believe it.
我還不信
- But here you are. - Here I am.
- 但你就在這裏
- 我在這裏
Bring me one of those chickens.
給我拿隻雞
- You got money to pay for it? - You paid for it?
- 你有錢嗎？
- 你給錢了？
No.
沒有
But we're the king's men.
但我們是國王的人
So, you got money?
你有錢嗎？
Not a penny.
一個子兒也沒有
I'll still take that chicken.
我還是要那隻雞
Tell you what.
這麼說吧
We'll trade you.
我跟你換
One of our little chickens for one of yours.
我的一隻雞換你的一隻雞
<i>Give us a go</i> <i>at your friend.</i>
<i>把你的朋友給我們</i>
Lowell there likes them a bit broken in.
那邊的洛威爾喜歡舊貨
You're a talker.
你真能說
Listening to talkers makes me thirsty.
聽能說的人講話我就渴了
And hungry.
也餓了
Think I'll take two chickens.
我要兩隻雞
You don't seem to understand the situation.
你還搞不清楚狀況
I understand that if any more words
我很清楚，再有一句話…
come pouring out of your cunt mouth,
從你臉上的屁眼裏出來
I'm gonna have to eat every fucking chicken in this room.
我就吃光這屋裏所有的雞
You lived your life for the king.
你為國王而活
You're gonna die for some chickens?
就為了幾隻雞尋死？
Someone is.
有人會死
Something wrong with your leg, boy?
你腿有問題嗎，小子？
What? What do you mean?
什麼？你什麼意思？
Can you walk? I've got to carry you?
你能走嗎？我得背著你？
Carry me?
背著我？
Fine little blade.
這把小劍還真不錯
Maybe I'll pick my teeth with it.
也許我會拿來剔牙
-=TLF字幕组=-
谢谢观赏
TLF中文字幕站 http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博地址：http://t.sina.com.cn/tlfsubs
豆瓣小站：http://site.douban.com/127446/